Louisiana Hayride Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 4. Elvis Presley and the Louisiana Hayride, 1956-1994
  - Photographic prints, circa 1954-2006 January
    - Elvis Presley and his band performing on stage at the Louisiana Hayride
      - Elvis Presley on stage with Scotty Moore, D.J. Fontana, and Bill Black in their final Louisiana Hayride performance, at the Hirsch Youth Building, Louisiana State Fairgrounds, Shreveport, 1956 December 15
        - Elvis Presley on stage with Scotty Moore, D.J. Fontana, and Bill Black, 1956 December 15, Kinel, Ben; 1 photographic print: black and white; 10 x 8 inches; RS 13857 P145 (Box-folder 9/27)
          From left to right: Scotty Moore, Elvis Presley, D.J. Fontana, Bill Black, Norm Bale, unidentified man, Frank Page.
          Handwritten on back of photographic print: "Norm Bale, Frank Page, Elvis Presley, Scotty Moore (guitar), Bill Black (bass), D.J. Fontana (drums)."
        - Elvis Presley on stage, 1956 December 15, [Kinel, Ben?]; 1 photographic print: black and white; 5 x 3 1/2 inches; RS 13857 P146 (Box-folder 9/27)
          Handwritten on reverse: "To Gentry: From Claudia. El at Louisiana Hayride about 1958."
          Written on reverse, in a different hand: "12-15-56."
        - Elvis Presley on stage with Scotty Moore, D.J. Fontana, and Bill Black, 1956 December 15, Kinel, Ben; 1 contact sheet: black and white; 10 x 8 inches; RS 13857 PC1 (Box-folder 9/27)
          Sheet contains three images, each about 5 x 3 3/4 inches, including the image that corresponds to Ben Kinel 10 x 8-inch print (RS 13857 P145).
        - Elvis Presley on stage with the Jordanaires, 1956 December 15, [Kinel, Ben?]; 1 contact sheet: black and white; 10 x 8 inches; RS 13857 PC2 (Box-folder 9/27)
          Sheet contains three images, each about 3 3/4 x 5 inches.
    - Elvis Presley with girlfriend, [Shirley Delgado?], circa 1955, 1 photographic print: black and white; 3 x 2 3/8 inches; RS 13857 P147 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Elvis Presley interacting with fans and giving interviews, circa 1956, 2 contact sheets: black and white; 10 x 4 inches and 8 x 5 inches; RS 13857 PC3; RS 13857 PC4 (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Scotty Moore performing on stage, circa late 1990s or early 2000s, 2 photographic prints: color; 8 x 12 inches and 12 x 8 inches; RS 13857 P148; RS 13857 P149 (Box-folder 9/29)
      see also Elvis Presley and his band performing on stage at the Louisiana Hayride.
    - Concert to celebrate the 50th anniversary of Elvis Presley's first appearance on the Louisiana Hayride, at the Municipal Auditorium, Shreveport, 2004 October 16, 16 photographic prints: color; 4 x 6 inches; RS 13857 P150–RS 13857 P1165 (Box-folder 9/30)
      Photographs show various performers on stage and individuals assembled backstage. Included are longtime Hayride announcer Frank Page, who emceed the show; members of the TCB Band (Taking Care of Business), a band that toured with Presley from circa 1969-1977 and included James Burton (guitar), Terry Mike Jeffrey (vocals), Jerry Scheff (bass), Ronnie Tutt (drums), and Glen D. Hardin (piano, not shown); D.J. Fontana (being interviewed by concert producer Darwin Lamm); and the Jordanaires. There are also photographs of the Elvis Presley statue in front of the Shreveport Municipal Auditorium and an Elvis Presley museum display.
      The photographs were in an envelope labeled: "E.P. 50th." The specific date written on the back of some of the photographs is 2006 January 6.
      For additional photographs of James Burton, see also David Houston and sixteen-year-old James Burton performing on stage at the Louisiana Hayride, 1956. For additional photographs of Frank Page, see also Frank Page with Louisiana Hayride performers and hosts, [between 1948 and 1958?] For additional photographs of D.J. Fontana, see also Elvis Presley and his band performing on stage at the Louisiana Hayride.
    - Frank Page and Tillman Franks at a celebration honoring Elvis Presley's 71st birthday, at the Municipal Auditorium, Shreveport, 2006 January 8, 5 photographic prints: color; 4 x 6 inches; RS 13857 P166–RS 13857 P170 (Box-folder 9/31)
- Series 5. Radio and Country Music Periodicals and Publications, 1916-2003
  Series 5 includes various radio, music, and local Louisiana periodicals. The country and rock and roll music periodicals and the local Louisiana periodicals feature articles related to the history of the Louisiana Hayride and KWKH radio.
  All materials were arranged alphabetically and chronologically within groupings.
  - Radio periodicals, 1916-1933
    - The Air Pilot, 1931 June-1932 February (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Andrew's Radio Directory and Log-Book, 1926 summer (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Horseless Age, 1916 December 1 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - International Radio Atlas, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - QST Magazine, 1921 March-1926 December
      - 1921 March-December (Box-folder 3/10)
      - 1922 November-December (Box-folder 3/11)
      - 1923 August-September (Box-folder 4/1)
      - 1924 September-1925 September (Box-folder 4/2)
      - 1926 August-September (Box-folder 4/3)
      - 1926 October-December (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Radio Age, 1923 September-1924 September (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Radio Broadcast, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Radio Digest, 1926 January 2-1930 January (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Radio News, 1929 February-1932 December
      - 1929 February-March (Box-folder 4/8)
      - 1929 May-December (Box-folder 4/9)
      - 1930 July-1932 December (Box-folder 5/1)
    - What's on the Air, 1930 October (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Country and rock and roll music periodicals, 1953-2003
    - Blue Suede News, 1999 winter (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Country Music, 1998 July-August (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Country Music People, 2003 September (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Country Song Roundup, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Cowboy Songs, number 22 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Folk and Country Songs, 1958 March-April (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Local Louisiana periodicals, 2000-2003
    - Louisiana Life, 2002-2003 winter (Box-folder 5/9)
    - SB Magazine, 2000 (Box-folder 5/10)
- Series 6. Songbooks and Sheet Music, 1931-1948, undated
  Series 6 includes collections of sheet music for various country music and gospel songs.
  Materials were arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Favorite Song Hits of the Rice Brothers and Their Radio Gang, 1942 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - "Louisiana Hayride" from the Musical Comedy Flying Colors, undated (Box-folder 5/12)
    Flying Colors was a musical revue (book, lyrics, and music by Arthur Schwartz and Howard Dietz) that ran on Broadway from September 1932 until January 1933 and included the song "Louisiana Hayride."
  - National Baptist Song Special, number one, 1941 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Songs of the Southland: as Presented by Buddy Jones, the Singing Cowboy, 1931 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - The Bailes Brothers Song Folio, number 2, 1948 (Box-folder 5/15)
- Series 7. Accompanying Descriptive Documentation, 1956-1987, undated
  - The Louisiana Hayride Archives, Including the KWKH Archives and the Early Shreveport Radio and Television Archives: an Illustrated Sampling of Assets, undated (Box 5)
  - Louisiana Hayride payroll ledger, 1960s (Box 7)
  - Collection catalogs and indices, 1951-1987
    - Graham Louisiana Hayride Audio Tape Collection catalog, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Kent Louisiana Hayride Digital Audio Tape Collection index, 1951 October 13-1985 October 17 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - The Louisiana Hayride, the David Kent shows, 1977-1987 (Box 6)
    - The Louisiana Hayride, secondary run playlists, circa 1977 (Box-folder 3/12)
      Additional playlists from the David Kent shows. These lists document radio program numbers 852, 854, 856-858, 860, 863-865.